{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Yeast are most likely to grow in frozen fruits during", "opta": "slow thawing", "optb": "refrigeration", "optc": "ambient temperature", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Watery soft rot is found mostly in", "opta": "fruits", "optb": "vegetables", "optc": "cereals", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Black mold rot is caused by", "opta": "A.flavus", "optb": "A. niger", "optc": "Trichoderma", "optd": "Trichothecium roseum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Concentrate of fruits and vegetable juices", "opta": "favor the growth of A. niger and A. flavus species", "optb": "favour the growth of yeast and of acid and sugar tolerant Leuconostoc and Lactobacillus species", "optc": "favor the growth of Saprophytic bacteria", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The predominant micro-organisms in frozen foods are", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "micro-coccus", "optc": "yeast and moulds", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anthracnose is a defect which can be observed as", "opta": "spotting of leaves", "optb": "spotting of seedpods", "optc": "spotting of fruits", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stem and rots caused by species of molds involve", "opta": "leaves of fruits", "optb": "stem ends of fruits", "optc": "spotting on vegetables", "optd": "spotting on fruits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Species of __________ are predominant on thawing vegetables like sweet corn and peas when the temperature of thawing is fairly low.", "opta": "Streptococcus", "optb": "Micrococcus", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Under what conditions food poisoning bacteria may grow and produce toxins in vegetables?", "opta": "When thawed vegetables are held at refrigerated temperature for any considerable period", "optb": "When thawed vegetables are held at room temperature for any considerable period", "optc": "When thawed vegetables are held below refrigerated temperature for any considerable period", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacterial soft rot is caused due to", "opta": "fermentation of pectin", "optb": "fermentation of sugars", "optc": "formation of ketones", "optd": "formation of amino acids", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Saprophytic bacteria cause", "opta": "sliminess or souring in piled, wet and heating vegetables", "optb": "brown rot in vegetables", "optc": "black rot in fruits", "optd": "bacterial soft rot", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The micro-organism which is present in both fresh and frozen juices is", "opta": "E. coli", "optb": "Entereobacter aerogenes", "optc": "P. chrysogenum", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}